
[
  {
    "question": "The following descriptions about complement system which one is CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "The highest concentration of the complement component in the serum is C5, that is why the patients with deficiency of C5 have recurrent infections.",
      "B": "There are 3 pathways, classical, lectin and alternative pathway. These pathways differ in how C3 is produced but follow a common sequence after C5 cleavage.",
      "C": "In classical pathway, both antigen-bound and antigen-free antibody can bind and activate C1 component.",
      "D": "Activated C3a and C5a can covalently bind to the bacterial cell wall and initiate phagocytosis"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第1題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Antimicrobial peptides (AMP) are part of innate immunity. Which of the statement is CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "AMPs have a selectivity against bacterial but not host cells.",
      "B": "AMPs are part of mechanical barrier to prevent the entry of pathogens.",
      "C": "AMPs are amphipathic peptides that have a hydrophilic end and a hydrophobic end.",
      "D": "AMPs are only secreted by immune cells but not nonimmune cells."
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第2題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "About phagocytosis, which is CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "The phagocytosis mechanism by neutrophil and macrophage is very different.",
      "B": "When antigen is phagocytosed by neutrophil and macrophage, the pH in the phagolysosomes of the cell will increase to digest the antigen.",
      "C": "Only macrophage but not neutrophil will secrets AMP when performing phagocytosis.",
      "D": "Only neutrophil but not macrophage will perform a special kind of apoptosis called NETosis, which releases its DNA to trap antigens."
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第3題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pattern recognition receptors (PRR) are expressed on most innate immune cells that can recognize pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMPs). Which of following statement is NOT CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "TLR4 requires MD2 to facilitate the binding of LPS, a key component of gram-negative bacterial cell wall.",
      "B": "PRRs are expressed on different compartments of immune cells, including plasma membrane, cytosol, endosome and nucleus.",
      "C": "NLR (Nod-like receptor), CLR (C-type lectin receptor), RLR (Rig-I like receptor), TLR (Toll-like receptor) and CDS (Cytosolic DNA sensor) all belong to PRR.",
      "D": "The binding of PAMP to PRR usually results in production of cytokines, including IL-6, TNFα and type I interferon."
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第4題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "In terms of antibody structure, which statement is CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "CDR1, 2, 3 both heavy chain and light chain determines the binding region structure with antigen.",
      "C": "The production of membrane bound or secreted form of IgM in a B cells is determined by DNA rearrangement."
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第5題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Monoclonal antibody (mAb) is important for treating diseases. Which statement concerning mAbs are CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Traditional way to make mAbs is to fuse a naive B cell with a tumor B cell line.",
      "B": "There is no way to make an mAb against an antibody because they are the same.",
      "C": "Anti-CTLA-4 and Anti-PD-1 antibodies are two mAbs successfully used to treat cancer patients.",
      "D": "Trastuzumab is a fully human antibody."
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第6題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Presentation of pre-B receptor is an important checkpoint in B cell development. Which statement concerning signal from pre-B receptor is CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Will inhibit light chain gene rearrangement",
      "B": "Will promote heavy chain gene rearrangement",
      "C": "Will promote surrogate light gene rearrangement",
      "D": "Will enhance pre-B cell proliferation"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第7題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding ITAM and ITIM, which is NOT CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Upon activation by tyrosine phosphorylation, ITAM recruits kinases to positively regulate immune response.",
      "B": "CTLA4 can negatively regulate T cell response by competing the binding of B7 with CD28 and simultaneously transduce negative signal.",
      "C": "T cell receptor (TCR) itself has 6 ITAMs in its intracellular domain to trigger signal events after engaging with MHC-peptide.",
      "D": "Immune checkpoint blockade for cancer treatment is using anti-CTLA-4 or anti-PD1 to inhibit the negative signals in T cells."
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第8題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Post-transcriptional modification like tyrosine phosphorylation is important for many reactions. Which statement is NOT CORRECT?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Tyrosine on the receptor is phosphorylated for initiation.",
      "B": "Scaffold protein is phosphorylated to recruit downstream molecules.",
      "C": "When the phosphate is removed by protein tyrosine phosphatase, the signal will be terminated.",
      "D": "Non-tyrosine kinase receptors use intracellular kinase domain to phosphorylate its downstream molecules."
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第9題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following signaling determines the commitment of T-cell lineage?",
    "options": {
      "A": "BCR",
      "B": "Notch",
      "C": "RAS",
      "D": "TCR",
      "E": "TLR"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第1題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mutant with MHC class I transgene that cannot interact with CD8:",
    "options": {
      "A": "Only CD4+ T",
      "B": "No CD4+ or CD8+ T",
      "C": "Only CD8+ T",
      "D": "Both CD4+ and CD8+ T"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第2題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Double-negative T cell with CD44+, CD25- markers:",
    "options": {
      "A": "DN1 T cell",
      "B": "DN2 T cell",
      "C": "DN3 T cell",
      "D": "DN4 T cell"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第3題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protein does not participate in RAG-dependent V(D)J Rearrangement?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Ku70",
      "B": "AID",
      "C": "TdT",
      "D": "Artemis",
      "E": "XRCC4"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第4題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the two gene segments are in the same transcriptional orientation in the germ line DNA, their DNA rearrangement involves X and Y of the DNA between them?",
    "options": {
      "A": "inversion and deletion",
      "B": "inversion and integration",
      "C": "looping-out and deletion",
      "D": "looping-out and integration"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第5題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "The exogenous pathway of loading peptide/antigen onto MHC class 1 is called cross-presentation and is actively practiced by X.",
    "options": {
      "A": "B cell",
      "B": "Dendritic cell",
      "C": "Hepatocyte cell",
      "D": "Macrophage",
      "E": "NK cell"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第6題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which feature of class I molecules is not correct?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Accommodate peptide of 8-11 residues",
      "B": "CD8 mainly binds to alpha 3 domain",
      "C": "Location of polymorphic are alpha 1 & 2 domain",
      "D": "Nomenclature are HLA-A/B/C in human",
      "E": "Polypeptide chains are Alpha and beta"
    },
    "answer": "E",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第7題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "下列關於 Class I MHC pathway 中的抗原處理與呈現，何者不正確？(原題目為英文)",
    "options": {
      "A": "所有有核的細胞都是 APC",
      "B": "CD8+ T cell is type of responsive T cell",
      "C": "ER 是 peptide load 到 MHC 上的地方",
      "D": "TAP-1/2參與了 peptide 的裝載與呈現"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第8題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following proteins is not a component of the peptide loading complex (PLC)?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Calreticulin",
      "B": "ERp57",
      "C": "LMP7",
      "D": "TAP",
      "E": "Tapasin"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第9題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "About superantigen, which is false?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Binds MHC class II.",
      "B": "Does not bind to the conventional peptide binding groove.",
      "C": "Bacterial superantigens bind mainly to the Vb CDR2 loop.",
      "D": "Viral superantigens bind mainly to the hypervariable 2 (HV2) loop.",
      "E": "Toxic shock syndrome toxin-1 (TSST-1) is a bacterial superantigen."
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第10題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "cytokine induce IgA?",
    "options": {
      "A": "IF-12",
      "B": "IL-4",
      "C": "TNF-α",
      "D": "TGF-β",
      "E": "IFN-γ"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第11題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which kind of cell expresses FcɛRI?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Neutrophil",
      "B": "Basophil",
      "C": "Macrophage",
      "D": "B cell",
      "E": "NK cell"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第12題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "CD4+T可促進APC表現X及B7,以活化 CD8+T,請問X為下列何者?(原題目為英文)",
    "options": {
      "A": "4-1BBL",
      "B": "CD28",
      "C": "CTLA-4",
      "D": "PD-1",
      "E": "TIM-3"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第13題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following cell-surface molecules is not expressed in activated T-cell?",
    "options": {
      "A": "CD44",
      "B": "CD45RO",
      "C": "VLA-4",
      "D": "L-selectin",
      "E": "PSLG-1"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第14題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "STAT6 is mainly expressed in which subset of CD4+ T cell?",
    "options": {
      "A": "T$_{H}$1",
      "B": "T$_{H}$2",
      "C": "T$_{H}$17",
      "D": "T$_{FH}$",
      "E": "T$_{reg}$"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第15題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of cytokine can be secreted by pDC?",
    "options": {
      "A": "IL-4",
      "B": "IL-17",
      "C": "IFN-α",
      "D": "IFN-γ",
      "E": "TGF-β"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第16題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following microbes is the target of TH2 cells?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Candida spp",
      "B": "Listeria spp",
      "C": "Klebsiella spp",
      "D": "Mycobacterium spp",
      "E": "Parasites"
    },
    "answer": "E",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第17題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Herd immunity is best described as",
    "options": {
      "A": "Vaccination of livestock herd",
      "B": "Protecting individuals who have not been vaccinated",
      "C": "Vaccinating the contacts of an infected person",
      "D": "Using multiple vaccines at one time",
      "E": "Protection of vaccinated individuals"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第1題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is wrong?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Using immunosuppressive drugs may cause increase the risk of infection",
      "B": "CAR-T include extracellular domain, transmembrane domain, and an intercellular signaling domain",
      "C": "Antibody can be engineered to increase immunogenicity by humanization",
      "D": "Tumor cells may be eliminated by the immune system, but as they evolve, variants occur and eventually escape immune surveillance and form tumor",
      "E": "HPV vaccine can prevent cervical cancer"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第5題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "About transplantation, which one is incorrect?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Thanks to immunosuppressive drug, MHC matching is no longer the major problem of transplantation.",
      "B": "Skin graft is B-cell mediated.",
      "C": "Major histocompatibility antigen matching is important.",
      "D": "Minor histocompatibility antigen matching is also important, too."
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第6題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are tenets of the hygiene hypothesis except",
    "options": {
      "A": "childhood exposure to microorganisms is increased.",
      "B": "widespread use of antibiotics interferes with the use and education of the immune system..",
      "C": "widespread immunization practices compromise the development of a fully functional immune response.",
      "D": "an increase in allergic disease in developed countries compared to developing countries.",
      "E": "antibiotic-driven selection of super bacteria perturbs the immune system."
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第7題]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following molecule(s) can transduce inhibitory signal to T cells? (select ALL that apply)",
    "options": {
      "A": "CD3",
      "B": "CD28",
      "C": "PD-1",
      "D": "4-1BB",
      "E": "B7",
      "F": "CTLA-4",
      "G": "CD25",
      "H": "CD20"
    },
    "answer": ["C", "F", "G"],
    "explanation": "\[出自考古第9題]"
  }
]
